SUBHAM CHAR

+91 9641867361

charvai1997@gmail.com

Manbazar, West Bengal, India



SUMMARY

With 4 years of experience, I specialize in **Full-Stack Development**, covering technologies like **JavaScript**, **React**, **Node.js**, **Express.js** and **MongoDB**. I also excel in using **AWS**, **TypeScript**, **Git**, and **Micro Frontends**, while **leading teams** and driving efficient solutions in **Blockchain** and **REST API** development.

SKILLS

• JavaScript • TypeScript • ReactJs • ExpressJs

Senior Software Engineer

- NodeJs MongoDB HTML CSS Git AWS
- SCSS Tailwind CSS Redux SocketIO REST APIs • NextJS • Firebase • React Query • Micro Frontend • Blockchain

EDUCATION

BENGAL COLLEGE OF ENGINEERING AND TECHNOLOGY

B.Tech (Information Technology) 2016 – 2020

MANBAR RADHA MADHAB INSTITUTION

12TH (Science) 2015 – 2016

MANBAR RADHA MADHAB INSTITUTION

10TH

2013 - 2014

CERTIFICATIONS

• The Complete Web Developer in 2020: Zero to Mastery

LINK

- linkedin.com/in/subham-char
- github.com/svarcoder
- svarcoder.github.io/my-website

LANGUAGES

- English
- Bengali
- Hindi

INTEREST

- Open-Source Contributation.
- · New Technology.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Arcana Network | Senior Software Developer

09/2024 - Present | Bengaluru, India

- Developed and Maintained Web App that used with React, Node, Express, MongoDB, AWS and Typescript.
- Working in **Frontend Technologies** for handle **React Application**.

Comdex | Senior Software Developer

04/2023 - 06/2024 | Bengaluru, India

- Developed and Maintained Web App that used with React, Node, Express, MongoDB, AWS and Typescript and Micro Frontend Technologies.
- Create and manage RESTFUL APIs In Node, Express, MongoDB to support the frontend.

Rapid Innovation | Software Developer

10/2021 - 03/2023 | Noida, India

- Lead Development Teams in the delivery of high-quality Frontend Application in React JS with Scalability, Performance, Security requirements.
- Manage User Authentication using JWT, Cross-Browser Compatibility.
 and Optimize the application for Performance and Responsiveness.

Techbae Pty Ltd | Full Stack Developer

10/2020 - 10/2021 | Melbourne, AU

- Developed and Maintained Web App that used with React, Node, Express, Mongo, AWS and Typescript managed by AWS Lambda, S3, API Gateway.
- **Deployed React.js** Application with **Redux**, **Typescript**, **CSS**, which contain multiple themes and in Backend in **Node**, **Express**, **MongoDB**.

PROJECTS

All In Bets

Technologies Used: MERN, Micro Frontend, TS, AWS

Design and Develope Frontend and Backend. Created APIs and Implemented in frontend. Also implement Socket and Firebase Notification with AWS Deployment.

White Label

Technologies Used: MERN, TypeScript, AWS

Design and Develope Frontend and Backend. Created APIs and Implemented in frontend.